<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Chronologies on Research Network BIOS</title>
    <link>http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chronologies on Research Network BIOS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-DE</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 11:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Network Meeting 2023</title>
      <link>http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/netzwerktreffen-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/netzwerktreffen-2023/</guid>
      <description>Announcement Next Meeting Network BIOS 2023</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We will get together June 14 - June 16 2023 in <a href="https://www.kuta-rauenthal.de">KuTa Rauenthal</a> (near Wiesbaden).</p>
<p>Details and futher info soon.</p>
<p>Please get in contact if you plan to participate: <a href="mailto:henning.fueller@geo.hu-berlin.de">henning.fueller@geo.hu-berlin.de</a> or <a href="mailto:iris.dzudzek@uni-muenster.de">iris.dzudzek@uni-muenster.de</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network meeting 2022 - /worlding bodies, situating technologies/ geography meets feminist STS</title>
      <link>http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/netzwerktreffen-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/netzwerktreffen-2022/</guid>
      <description>Bericht Netzwerktreffen in Burgdorf</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Date: 01. Juni - 03. Juni 2022, <a href="https://schloss-burgdorf.ch/en/">Schloss Burgdorf</a> in Switzerland</li>
<li>Team: Carolin Schurr, Iris Dzudzek, Susanne Hübl</li>
</ul>
<p>All sorts of technologies – old and new, analog and digital, medical and economic, big and small, quotidian and extraordinary etc. – are changing and challenging the constitution and limits of our body. The current pandemic once more shows how sick and healthy bodies arise in ecological and social relationality. They emerge from interscalar entanglements ranging from the microscopic scale of viruses and bacteria to global health politics. Un/healthy bodies are unevenly distributed across the globe with the pandemic showing the uneven intersec- tional geography of access to medical technologies and health infrastructures – not only a global but also national and local scale.</p>
<h2 id="program">Program</h2>
<h3 id="introduction-panel">Introduction Panel</h3>
<ul>
<li>Introducing Key Concepts of Feminist Technoscience (Jutta Weber)</li>
<li>Bodies and Populations - Feminist Perspectives on Reproduction (Susanne Schultz)</li>
<li>Bodies as/in space – an interdisciplinary panel discussion: Conceptualising space (Judith Miggelbrink) | Bodies as/in space (Carolin Schurr) | Worlding health (Iris Dzudzek)</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="workshops">Workshops</h3>
<ul>
<li>Workshop A: Global health (Henning Füller)</li>
<li>Workhshop B: Obstetric violence (Roberto Castro, in Spanish)</li>
<li>Workshopo C: Body and Knowledge, Disability and Science (Heidi Kaspar)</li>
<li>Workshop D: Reproductive Justice - Julieta Chaparro-Buitrage &amp; Yolinliztli Pérez-Hernández</li>
<li>E. Worlding with and through data (technologies) (Katrin Amelang)</li>
<li>Group discussion a: App-nographies: Positioning oneself in feminist technopolitical research Mara Linden &amp; Tilma*n Treier</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="reponse-ability-group-discussions">Reponse-ability: Group discussions</h3>
<ul>
<li>App-nographies: Positioning oneself in feminist technopoliticalresearch
(Mara Linden &amp; Tilma*n Treier)</li>
<li>Science communication: Bringing feminist technoscience intopolitics
(Laura Perler, Carolin Schurr and Sara Lafuente Funes)</li>
<li>Experimenting with bodily methods (Susanne Hübl)</li>
<li>Activist and creative research: Academia, activism and art (Iris Dzudzek)</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network meeting 2021 - BIOS afternoon</title>
      <link>http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/netzwerktreffen-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/netzwerktreffen-2021/</guid>
      <description>Network meeting 2021 - BIOS Nachmittag via Zoom</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Date: 12. November via Zoom</li>
<li>Team: Iris Dzudzek, Henning Füller, Carlin Schurr</li>
</ul>
<p>Following up with previous meetings, this afternoon provided the opportunity to discuss current state of work and thoughts:</p>
<ul>
<li>Caro, Laura and Nora reflect on their project „Reproductive Geopolitics“ .</li>
<li>Henning and Iris würden discuss thoughts regarding the change of space-based health politics and policies in the city post-COVID.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network meeting 2018 - Bioeconomy, Governmental Practices and the Production of Space</title>
      <link>http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/netzwerktreffen-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/netzwerktreffen-2018/</guid>
      <description>Program of the meeting in Leipzig 2018</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Date: 18.01. - 19.01. 2018, Institut für Geographie, Uiniversität Leipzig</li>
<li>Team: Judith Miggelbrink, Tom Schwarzenberg, Frank Meyer</li>
</ul>
<p>In Kooperation mit dem SFB 1199 <em>Processes of Saptialization under the Global Condition</em></p>
<p><a href="https://bios-net.github.io/dokumente/BIOS_Leipzig_Programm-2018.pdf">Program Bios 2018 Leipzig (pdf)</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network meeting 2016 - Kick-off Meeting</title>
      <link>http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/netzwerktreffen-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bios-net.github.io/en/chronologie/netzwerktreffen-2016/</guid>
      <description>Bericht Kick-off Meeting in Frankfurt</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Date: 24. Juni - 26. Juni 2016, Institut für Humangeographie, Frankfurt am Main</li>
<li>Team: Anke Strüver, Iris Dzudzek, Henning Füller</li>
</ul>
<p>In den vergangenen Jahren sind zahlreiche sehr interessante Arbeiten entstanden, die sich aus spannenden Perspektiven „im Nachgang des cultural turn“ mit Fragen rund um Gesundheit und Raum auseinandersetzen. Und ihr habt sie geschrieben.</p>
<p>Zu nennen sind hier die Forschung von Heidi Kaspar zu Medizintourismus und globalen Gesundheitsmärkten. Die Auseinandersetzung von Karin Schwiters und Anke Strüver zu transnationalen care Märkten. Caro Schurrs Projekt zu internationalen Leihmütter-Märkten. Anke Strüvers Reflexionen zu Körpern und Fitness im Neoliberalismus. Henning Füller und Jonathan Everts Arbeiten über die biopolitische Dimension von Pandemien im Spannungsfeld von Risiko und Sicherheit. Mathias Lahr-Kurtens Auseinandersetzung mit Praktiken auf Frühgeborenen-Stationen, Klaus Geiselharts Reflexionen über das Verhältnis von modernen Ärzten und spirituellen Heilern. Annika Zeddels Überlegungen zu salutogenetischen Gesundheitskonzepten. Iris Dzudzeks Projekt über das Reisen alternativer Heilpraktiken &hellip;</p>
<h2 id="program">Program</h2>
<h3 id="block-i-future-and-emergence-meike-wolf-und-henning-füller">Block I: Future and Emergence (Meike Wolf und Henning Füller)</h3>
<h3 id="block-ii-circulation-and-regulation-judith-miggelbrink-und-iris-dzudzek">Block II: Circulation and Regulation (Judith Miggelbrink und Iris Dzudzek)</h3>
<h3 id="impulse-talks">Impulse talks</h3>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
